ALISTER MACQUARRIE DODDS

<u>LinkedIn</u> alistermacquarrie@gmail.com 07508848408

Friendly, thoughtful and always curious, with experience in media and library services. I love history, film, and the natural world, and am an avid reader in my free time. My current freelance role has helped me develop research and organisational skills learned on my BA and MA degrees. I am used to hitting tight deadlines and working self-sufficiently, though I prefer being part of a close team where I can collaborate with and learn from others. In addition to excellent written and spoke communication skills, I'm adept with Office programmes like Word and Excel; as well as more specialised tools like Photoshop, Premiere Pro, and some generative AI.

EXPERIENCE

ZOMBIES, RUN! 2019 - current

Scriptwriter

Part-time script writing, development, and editing work for Naomi Alderman on her mobile game *Zombies*, *Run!*

FREELANCE WORK 2018 - current

Reviews, essays, and features on film, TV, and videogames. Articles published in *Rock Paper Shotgun, Eurogamer, New Socialist* and *Fanbyte*.

KING'S COLLEGE LONDON LIBRARY SERVICES 2014 - 17

Library Assistant

Work in the Special Collections department at the Maughan Library, incorporating donated material from the Foreign & Commonwealth Office into the collection; also general administration and data entry.

PIVOT THEATRE 2013 - 15

Creative Associate

Co-wrote and co-produced a 2-year theatre project, GULF. Developed and workshopped the show with the director, composer, and actors.

CHICHESTER FESTIVAL THEATRE 2013 - 14

Script Consultant

Script reading, editing, and development work on Chichester Festival Theatre's Out of the Archive project.

PELL & BALES 2012

Charity Fundraiser

Fundraising work in a call centre for charities including RSPCA and British Heart Foundation.

EDUCATION

Spanish Level 2 2024 - 25

University of Sussex

20-week adult education course at the University of Sussex.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP 2024

JustIT

12-week full-time course in software and website development.

MA SCRIPTWRITING 2016 - 17

Goldsmiths, University of London

Accredited Masters programme focused on professional screenwriting to an industry standard.

CITY ACADEMY SHORT FILM COURSE 2015

Short film course at City Academy with Martin Stitt, involving camera work, sound recording, directing, storyboarding and editing.

FIRST CLASS BA (Hons) in HISTORY 2011 - 14

King's College London

Awarded scholarship in 2012 for academic excellence and work with student theatre.

YOUNG PLAYWRIGHTS COURSE 2010 - 12

Selected for two consecutive Chichester Festival Theatre courses, ending with rehearsed readings of the best writing.

A LEVELS & GCSEs 2008 - 2011

Politics, History, Classics, and English Literature A levels (all A grade); 5 A or A* GCSEs including English Language and Literature, Media Studies, History, and Biology.

REFERENCES

Rebecca Levene

Producer, Zombies Run soggoth@hotmail.com

Philip Palmer

Senior Lecturer in Creative Writing Goldsmiths, University of London London SE14 5NW p.palmer@gold.ac.uk

Katie Sambrook

Head of Special Collections, King's College London Library Services Foyle Special Collections, Maughan Library London WC21 1LR catherine.sambrook@kcl.ac.uk